A Guide to the Scrapbooks of John William Flannagan 1920-1953
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Scrapbooks of John Flannagan 1920-1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10714
22 items
The collection contains 22 bound volumes of newsclippings, election returns, letterbooks, and speeches, 1920-1950, documenting Flannagan's political career.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Francis W. Flannagan, Bristol, Va.
Biographical/Historical Information
John William Flannagan (1885-1955), was a Congressman from the 9th Virginia district.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains thirteen volumes of newsclippings, 1920-1950, documenting Flannagan's political career; one volume of election returns, 1933-1938; one volume re: the Flannagan tobacco grading bill; three volumes re: the nomination of Judge Floyd Roberts as a Federal judge for the Western Virginia district; a letterbook; and three volumes of speeches chiefly from the Congressional Record.
The letterbook contains routine correspondence and many responses to his speech on his dog and to the Bankhead-Flannagan bill to fund agricultural extension work, as well as photographs.
Correspondents include Dean Acheson, James M. Beck, Schuyler O. Bland, Harry F. Byrd, Sr., Martin Dies, Jr., John F. Dockweiler, James A. Farley, Wilson Gee, Carter Glass, Marvin Jones, Edward C. Moran, George C. Peery, Samuel B. Pettingill, John E. Rankin, Sam Rayburn, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Morris Sheppard, Fred M. Vinson and Claude A. Swanson.
Miscellaneous items include an 1826 letter from Prof. Edward Grabhorn of Washington College re: James Lyle; a eulogy for Flannagan; and drafts of some of his speeches.
Contents List
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1920-1942 (Volume 1)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1930 Feb 16-Nov 1 (Volume 2)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1930 Nov 1-1933 Oct 15 (Volume 3)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1933 Oct 15-1935 Dec 31 (Volume 4)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings (Volume 5)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings (Volume 6)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1939 Jan 1-1940 May 1 (Volume 7)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1940 May 1-Nov 15 (Volume 8)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1940 Nov 15-1941 Dec 31 (Volume 9)
- Personal Nespaper Clippings 1942 Jan 1-1943 Apr (Volume 10)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1943 Apr-1944 Dec 1 (Volume 11)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1944 Dec 1-1950 Oct (Volume 12)
- Personal Newspaper Clippings 1946-1953 (Volume 13)
- Election Returns 1933-1938 (Volume 14)
- Flannagan Tobacco Grading Bill 1935-1936 (Volume 15)
- Judge Floyd Roberts (newspaper clippings) 1939 Jan 1-Feb 8 (Volume 16)
- Judge Floyd Roberts (newspaper clippings) 1939 Feb 8-13 (Volume 17)
- Judge Floyd Roberts (Newspaper clippings) 1939 Feb 14-1941 Apr (Volume 18)
- Letterbook 1924-1948 (Volume 19)
- Speeches from Congressional Record 1931 Dec-1934 Mar (Volume 20)
- Speeches from Congressional Record 1931 Dec-1937 July (Volume 21)
- Speeches from Congressional Record 1933 Mar-1942 Dec (Volume 22)
- Miscellaneous 1826 (1930-1963), n.d., Loose papers removed from bound volumes.
- Speeches by John W. Flannagan, Jr. 1932-1942, Loose papers removed from bound volumes; not printed.
- Speeches by John W. Flannagan, Jr. 1933-1938, n.d., Loose papers removed from bound volumes; from Congressional Record.